PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- Okay, so let's step back to the larger problem.
- 好啦 让我们回到一个比较大的问题上
Our finished movies are viewed
我们的电影最终用
in a number of different ways.
很多不同的途径播放
For instance, the screen a movie is displayed on
例如 放映电影的屏幕
could be a monitor, like this, or a projector, like this,
可以是一个监视器 像这个 或是一个投影仪 像这个
and that's where another problem creeps up.
这就产生了另一个新问题
Both of these displays are getting the same color signal
所有这些显示器都获得了同一个
of pure red.
纯红的信号
Notice these resulting colors we see
注意到我们看到的最终的颜色
aren't exactly the same.
并非完全一致
The problem is display devices,
问题就是 显示设备
like monitors and projectors,
比如监视器和投影仪
can only reproduce some of the perceivable colors.
仅能产生部分的可感知色彩
It's the pure, or single wavelength,
纯色或称为单波长光
red, green and blue light, they have trouble creating.
也就是红蓝黄三色光的产生有问题
Notice, this screen can generate a slightly purer,
可以看到 这块屏幕可以产生稍微纯一些的
or deeper, red compared to this one.
或稍微深一些红色 相较于这块
Remember, on our CIE diagram that the purest
还记的 在我们的 CIE 色度图中
red, green, and blue are way out on the edge,
纯的红绿蓝远远地落在边缘上
here, here, and here.
这里、这里和这里
But, a typical RGB monitor can't create anything close
但是 一个典型的 RGB 监视器无法产生任何与
to pure red, green, and blue light.
纯红绿蓝光相近的颜色
If it tries to display those colors,
如果它想显示这些颜色
the best it can do is hit three points
它能产生的最远三点就是
over here, here, and here.
这里、者里和这里
And, since the display can blend those colors,
然后 由于显示器可以混合它们
the device has the ability to create any colors
一个设备就可以创造出任何落在
in this black triangle.
这个黑色三角形中的颜色
This region is called the Gamut of the display device.
这个区域被称为显示设备的色域
It's the range of the perceivable colors
这是给定设备可产生的
any give device can reproduce.
可感知色彩的范围
Mathematicians would say the Gamut is a subset
数学家会说某个色域是
of the perceivable color space.
可感知色彩空间的一个子集
The size of this set is important to filmmakers
这个集合的大小对于电影创作者来说很重要
because they want the biggest palate of colors
因为他们想拿着最大的调色盘
to paint from.
来画画
More color means more artistic freedom.
更多的颜色意味着更大的艺术自由
For a long time, our movies were projected on film
很长一段时间 我们的电影都是用胶片投影的
which has a very large Gamut, like this.
它具有很大的色域 想这样
Eventually, we moved to digital projectors
最终 我们转向了数字投影仪
which had a different Gamut compared to film.
它和胶片有着不一样的色域
More recently, laser illuminated digital projectors
就在最近 激光照明的数字投影仪
have been introduced
已经问世
which have a much larger Gamut than film.
它比胶片具有更加广阔的色域
This is because they use laser light
这是因为它们使用激光
which is very close to a single wavelength
激光和单色光很相近
allowing them to produce very pure reds, greens, and blues.
可以产生非常纯的红色、绿色和蓝色
But here's a practical problem for you to think about.
但这里有一个你需要思考的实际问题
How do we make sure our movies look good on any device,
该如何保证我们的电影在任何设备上都很好看
especially if they have very different Gamuts?
特别是如果它们具有非常不同的色域？
You can think about that while working
你可以一边做下面的练习
on the next exercise. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
一边思考这个问题 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox